A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Action Control Slips FA749
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Action Control Slips
1957-1966
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA749
24 Microform Reels 24 microfilm reels
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for scholarly research.
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment.
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Related Materials
For the Ford Foundation Central Index, please refer to the following findng aid:
FA736 Ford Foundation records, Central Index, 1950-1996
Arrangement
Action Controls Slips are arranged by year, then alphabetically by the correspondent’s last name, or organizational name.
Scope and Contents
Action Control Slips were used by the Ford Foundation to route incoming correspondence and project proposals. The Action Control Slips can be used in conjunction with the Ford Foundation’s Central Index cards (FA736) to identify where correspondence was filed within the Ford Foundation’s central records (Grant files, Project files, Log files, and General Correspondence files).
For instance, a 1960 letter from John Apple to the Ford Foundation may be indexed as “GEN 60, APPLE…..” by the Central Index cards. For further information on the routing, filing, and action taken in response to this letter, the Action Control Slips should be consulted.
Ford Foundation
- A-Z, 1957 (Reel 1)
- A-LOU, 1958 (Reel 1)
- LOU-Z, 1958 (Reel 2)
- A-Z, 1959 (Reel 3)
- A-HAC, 1960 (Reel 3)
- HAC-Z, 1960 (Reel 4)
- A-MIA, 1961 (Reel 5)
- MIA-Z, 1961 (Reel 6)
- A-DAC, 1962 (Reel 6)
- DAC-SEA, 1962 (Reel 7)
- SEA-Z, 1962 (Reel 8)
- A-GAF, 1963 (Reel 8)
- GAF-RAD, 1963 (Reel 9)
- RAD-Z, 1963 (Reel 10)
- A-GAL, 1964 (Reel 10)
- GAL-NAB, 1964 (Reel 11)
- NAB-Z, 1964 (Reel 12)
- A-LAB, 1965 (Reel 13)
- LAB-SAB, 1965 (Reel 14)
- SAB-Z, 1965 (Reel 15)
- A-N, 1966 (Reel 16)
- O-Z, 1966 (Reel 17)
- A-L, 1967 (Reel 18)
- M-Z, 1967 (Reel 19)
- A-L, 1968 (Reel 20)
- M-Z, 1968 (Reel 21)
- A-F, 1969 (Reel 22)
- G-SH, 1969 (Reel 23)
- SI – Z, 1969 (Reel 24)